# Jsman Maqbool **Bhutta**

Room 2008 (25), Robotics Institute, 2nd Floor, CYT Building, Lift(35-36), HKUST

🛘 (+852) 6843-2892 | 🗷 mumbhutta@connect.ust.hk | 🎢 usmanmaqbool.github.io | 🛅 usmanmaqbool | 🖏 usman17888

"Do it with passion or not at all."

#### Summary.

Current co-founder of a start-up company Lisee Technology Corporation. 5+ years experience specializing in project management for research and development, web development and marketing at Friends Corporate Technologies. I have been a part of some other startups related to real estate, marketing, and automation. A super nerd who loves entrepreneurship, deep learning, and enjoys to develop the idea to reality. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises..

#### **Education**

#### The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology - HKUST

(Kowloon, Hong Kong)

Sep. 2016 - Present

Ph.D. Candidate, Department of Electronic & Computer Engineering

- · Got PEEF Pakistan scholarship to pursuing my studies
- · Research interests; Multi-Agent SLAM System and autonomous car driving

#### Quaid-i-Azam University - QAU

Islamabad, Pakistan

M.PHIL. ELECTRONICS, DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRONICS

- · Research: Signal and Image Processing
- Grade: 1st Division (80% Marks)

Quaid-i-Azam University - QAU

Mar. 2010 - Jun. 2012

#### Islamabad, Pakistan

M.Sc. Electronics, Department of Electronics

Mar. 2010 - Jun. 2012

- · 2nd position in batch
- Grade: 1 st Division (74.6% marks)

#### **Bahauddin Zakariya University - BZU**

Multan, Pakistan

B.Sc. in Mathematics and Physics

Mar. 2010 - Jun. 2012

· Grade: 1st Division

### **Research Publications**

### Multiple Lane Detection Algorithm Based on Optimised Dense Disparity Map Estimation

Conference Paper

Han Ma, Yixin Ma, Jianhao Jiao, M Usman Maqbool Bhutta, Mohammud Junaid Bocus, Lujia Wang, Ming Liu, Rui Fan Accepted in IEEE International Conference on Imaging Systems and Techniques (IST) 2018

Oct 2018

#### PCR-Pro: 3D Sparse and Different Scale Point Clouds Registration and Robust Estimation of Information Matrix For Pose Graph SLAM

Conference Paper

M USMAN MAQBOOL BHUTTA, MING LIU

Jul 2018

Presented in IEEE Int. Conf. on CYBER Technology in Automation, Control, and Intelligent Systems, and won Best Student Paper Finalist Award.

#### An intelligent approach for robust detection and recognition of multiple color and font styles automobiles license plates: A feature-based algorithm

Conference Paper

M USMAN MAQBOOL BHUTTA, HASAN MAHMOOD, AND HAROON MALIK

Jul 2014

Published in IEEE International Conference on Audio, Language and Image Processing (ICALIP).

#### **Efficient Reset Design Techniques**

Journal Paper

OAMAR, ZOHA, BUSHRA YASEEN, AND USMAN MAOBOOL

2015

Published in Science International Lahore

# Work Experience \_

INDUSTRY

#### **Friends Corporate Technologies**

Islamabad, PK Feb 2013 - Aug 2015

May 2012 - Feb 2013

Feb 2016 - Jun 2016

50+ Projects | Electronics/ Electrical Engineering, R&D, image processing, Web Applications Development, MVC Applications

**Federal Government of Pakistan** Islamabad, PK

SCIENTIFIC OFFICER Electronics/ Electrical Engineering, R&D, image processing

Server4Sale, LLC Islamabad, PK

PHP DEVELOPER Dec 2009 - Mar 2010

Php web application development for Joomla and Zend frameworks.

**ACADEMIC** 

**Department of Computer Science** BZU sub campus Sahiwal, PK

LECTURER (VISITING)

Teaching MCS and BS-CS courses

Government PG College Sahiwal, PK

**Department of Physics** 

Aug. 2014 - Apr. 2016

Teaching BS physics (Electronics related courses + Labs + Projects)

## **Academic Activities**

Fall 2018 <b>Teaching Assistant</b> , ELEC4820 - Medical Imaging	HKUST, HK
2018 <b>Referee Service</b> , IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems	IROS 2018
Spr 2018 <b>Teaching Assistant</b> , EESM 5547 - Multimedia Signal Processing	HKUST, HK
Spr 2017 <b>Teaching Assistant,</b> ELEC 1010 - Electronic and Information Technology	HKUST, HK

#### Honors & Awards \_\_

#### INTERNATIONAL

Best Student Paper Finalist Award, IEEE Int. Conf. on CYBER Technology in Automation, Control, and	Tianiin China
July, 2018 Intelligent Systems	Tianjin, China
May, 2018 Best Proposal Audience Award, Campus Challenge - Transportation, HKUST	HKUST, HK
Nov, 2017 Best Mapper Award, Robotics and Multi-Perception Lab, HKUST	Shenzhen, China
May, 2017 <b>Completion Award</b> , The Graduate Teaching Assistant Training, HKUST	HKUST, HK
Dec, 2016 Best External Award, Robotics and Multi-Perception Lab, HKUST	Shenzhen, China
Nov, 2016 <b>Completion Award</b> , Author Workshop, Elsevier Publishing Campus	HKUST, HK

#### **DOMESTIC**

Sep 2013	<b>Participant</b> , Painting for peace (Pakistan-India-Afghanistan) event, a part of the Harmony initiative	Islamabad, PK
Apr 2013	Participant, Case Spark in business plan competition	Islamabad, PK
Apr 2013	Participant, Case EPICA	Islamabad, PK
Apr 2013	Participant, How to be a Better Playwright Workshop by PNCA and US Embassay Pakistan	Islamabad, PK
Oct 2012	Participant, Punjab Youth Festival	Lahore, PK
Oct 2011	Participant, Int'l Youth Conference and Festival	Islamabad, PK
Sep 2011	Participant, Asian Youth Conference and Peace Festival	Lahore, PK
Apr 2011	<b>Completion Award</b> , Acting and Directing Theater Workshop by PNCA and US Embassay Pakistan	Islamabad, PK
Dec 2011	Participant, National Drama Festival	Islamabad, PK
Dec 2010	Instuctor of short Course, PHP Web Development' at the Department of Electronics, QAU	Islamabad, PK
Apr 2013	Completion Award, Running River Rafting course by Adventure Foundation of Pakistan	Mansehra, PK
Apr 2013	Completion Award, Paragliding course by QAU Adventure Club	Islamabad, PK
Dec 2008	Award of Honor, Finance Secretary of Electronics Student Society (ESS) at QAU	Islamabad, PK